Dan Whiting

Policy and Communications Strategist

Summa	ary
-------	-----

Over the past 18 years, I have worked in all aspects of public policy, including legislative, communications, regulatory, marketing, and grassroots engagement. Understanding each of the areas helps me to more effectively affect change because I see how each influences the other so the whole campaign is coordinated.

Employment

2011-Present

Senior Strategist, ADG Creative, Columbia, MD

Provide strategy and program management for marketing/communication campaigns; manage client relationships, internal teams, and projects; write scripts, proposals, articles, blog posts, and ad copy; develop new business

2009-2011

Director of Communications, National Alliance of Forest Owners, Washington, DC

Supported advocacy with strategic communications; developed grassroots/grasstops network and ran a multi-state grasstops campaign; outreached to media; wrote press releases, web content, letters, and white papers; oversaw academic research; built coalitions

2008-2009

Chief of Staff, Natural Resources Conservation Service, Washington, DC Managed the Office of the Chief of the NRCS; built support for the President's priorities with staff and partners; coordinated headquarters' budget development; oversaw implementation of the 2008 Farm Bill

1997-2008

U.S. Senator Larry Craig

2006-2008

Communications Director, Washington, DC

Orchestrated all external and internal communications; developed proactive and reactive strategies; executed crises communications; served as the primary spokesman for the Senator; hired and managed a staff of seven; pushed early adoption of new media channels; integrated mail, press, web, and Spanish-language communications under one umbrella

2004-2006

Press Secretary, Washington, DC

Primary spokesman for DC press; wrote press releases, speeches, op-eds, and website copy; developed relationships with Idaho and national reporters

Dan Whiting

Policy and Communications Strategist

2001-2004	Regional Director, Coeur d'Alene, ID Networked with grassroots/grasstops leaders to understand the communities, legislators, key leaders and influencers and to deliver Senator Craig's messages; focused on economic development, mining, forestry, public lands, and healthcare
1999-2001	Legislative Assistant, Washington, DC Advised the Senator on university research funding, energy and natural resources, public lands, environment, and wildlife; built coalitions; crafted legislation and talking points; met with constituent groups and agencies; delivered remarks
1997-1999	Legislative Correspondent, Washington, DC Crafted letters to constituents on energy, environment, natural resources, public lands, agriculture, and education
Education	
2015	Front End Web Development, General Assembly Learned HTML, CSS, and JavaScript; developed an intuitive, cross- platform Congressional Directory (www.capitolview.us)
2004-2005	M.A. Management and Entrepreneurship, Regent University Developed a business plan for a lobbying firm that combines lobbying, media, and grassroots/grasstops efforts
1991-1996	B.S. Human Resource Management, University of Idaho President Pro Tempore for the Student Senate and lobbyist for the
Other	student body for the 1994 Idaho legislative session
Experience	
Present	Write on marketing, advocacy, and innovation <u>Association Marketer</u> <u>Brain Juice</u>
2008	Spokesman while a worker was kidnapped in Afghanistan Asian Rural Life Development Foundation
2005-2008	Lecturer on Media Relations and Writing on Capitol Hill Leadership Institute

6004 Euclid St, Cheverly, MD 20785 · (202) 531-9091 · <u>dan@danwhiting.com</u> <u>@danwhiting · hire.danwhiting.com · LinkedIn</u>